Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office. Terry Bullen Papers, 1979-2002 and undated
The John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office. Terry Bullen papers 1979-2002 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office.
1.5 Linear Feet 800 Items
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. The JWT London Office opened in 1899. Terry Bullen was an advertising executive at the JWT London Office who worked in New Business and as Director of Planning before retiring in 2001.
The J. Walter Thompson Company London Office Terry Bullen Papers span the years 1979-2002 and consist primarily of presentations and research reports made by JWT. Clients represented include Allied Breweries, Ansell's Bitter (Carlsberg), Beconase (GlaxoSmithKline), British Airports Authority (BAA), Esso, Golden Wonder, Mr. Kipling, Tetley, and Warner Lambert Health Care. Also included are videocassettes, CD-R's and awards information. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
In addition, original audiovisual materials are closed to patron use. Research Services staff need to produce use copies before contents can be accessed.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office. Terry Bullen Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2003.
Biographical Note
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. The JWT London Office opened in 1899. Terry Bullen was an advertising executive at the JWT London Office who worked in New Business and as Director of Planning before retiring in 2001.
Collection Overview
The J. Walter Thompson Company London Office Terry Bullen Papers span the years 1979-2002 and consist primarily of presentations and research reports made by JWT. Clients represented include Allied Breweries, Ansell's Bitter (Carlsberg), Beconase (GlaxoSmithKline), British Airports Authority (BAA), Esso, Golden Wonder, Mr. Kipling, Tetley, and Warner Lambert Health Care. Also included are videocassettes, CD-R's and awards information.
Collection Arrangement
Collection is arranged into two series: Terry Bullen Papers, and Audiovisual Materials, alphabetically therein.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Bullen, Terry
J. Walter Thompson Company
J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office
Allied Breweries
British Airports Authority
Carlsberg bryggerierne
Esso UK (Firm)
GlaxoSmithKline
Warner-Lambert Company
Advertising -- History
Advertising -- Great Britain -- History
Advertising agencies
Advertising agencies -- Great Britain
Advertising agencies -- Great Britain -- History
Advertising executives
Advertising executives -- Great Britain
CD-Rs
Videocassettes
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Related Material
Colin Dawkins Papers
International Advertisements Collection
London Office Records
London Office. Sam Soper Papers
Newsletters
Publications
Thomas Sutton Papers
Contents of Collection
- Terry Bullen Papers, 1979-1999 and undated
  - General
    - Effective Advertising: 8 Case Studies, 1980 Nov. (Box 1)
    - Our Best Total Branding, 1999
  - Allied Breweries: Skol
    - A presentation to Allied Breweries from JWT, 1985, (2 folders)
    - Presentation: Advertising Recommendations 1985-90, 1985 July
  - Ansell's Bitter
    - Advertising Recommendations to Ansell's Bitter, 1986 May
  - BAA PLC
    - Presentation of Corporate Advertising Proposals, 1990 May
    - Research Study: Institutional Investors and Analysts in Great Britain, 1990
    - Research Study: Survey of Britain's Editors, 1990
  - Beconase
    - Advertising and Media Strategy, 1994 Jan.
  - Esso
    - Building the Esso Brand for the 1990s: Exploratory Qualitative Research, 1990 Mar.
    - Competitive Advertising Review of Petroleum Industry 1989-1991, 1991
    - Corporate Press Advertising Survey (Report), 1991 Dec. (Box 2)
    - Esso 1992 Campaign Development: Exploratory Qualitative Research, 1991 Dec.
    - Esso 1992 Campaign Development: Exploratory Qualitative Research, 1992 Jan.
    - JWT London Reponse to Esso Petroleum's Invitation to Bid for Retail, Corporate, and Lubricant Business, 1991 Sept., (2 folders)
    - Presentation: Corporate Press Advertising Survey, 1991 Dec.
    - Presentation: strategic, Media, and Creative Recommendations, 1991 Oct., (2 folders)
    - Public Opinion Monitor, 1991 Oct.
    - Public Opinion Monitor Review of New Format, 1992 Feb.
    - Report: The Exclusion of the Third Inserted Advert, 1992 Jan.
    - Research Study: Attitudes of Members of Parliament, 1991
    - Research study: Survey of Britain's Business and Financial Journalists, 1989
  - Eurotunnel
    - A Presentation to Eurotunnel from JWT London and Paris, undated, (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Golden Wonder Crisps
    - A Presentation of Advertising and Marketing Proposals, 1982 Feb.
  - Mr. Kipling (brand of baked goods)
    - Mr. Kipling: A Life, undated
  - Tetley Bitter
    - A Presentation on Tetley Bitter Advertising, 1988 Jan.
  - Warner Lambert Health Care
    - Benylin: A Record of the Presentation, 1988 Mar.
    - Listermint: Rothermere Radio Research Award 1979: Establishing Radio's Contribution to the Effectiveness of the Sloosh, 1979 July
- Audiovisual Materials
  - Originals
    - Mr. Kipling History Reel 1967-1991 (72 ads). 1991. Format: Umatic. TRT: 35:00 (Box 4)
    - TTB 2001 Awards Highly Commended. Format: Powerpoint CD-R. 2002